# 哈喽 大家好
Hello guys
# 这个鸭子是我们去年没修房子之前买的鸭苗
This duck was once the little duckling we bought last year before we built this house
# 喂到现在
It has been feeded until now
# 喂了好久了安四伯爷
Uncle, it's been feeded quite a while, right?
# 喂了一年多了 去年栽秧子的时候买的嘛
It's more than a year. Didn't we buy it last year when we planted the seedlings?
# 吃了我们很多粮食长到了应该有五六斤了嘎
It has eaten lots of our grains. It should weigh about 5 or 6 "Jin" ("Jin":500g)
# 嗯
Um
# 五六斤是有的
Should have 5 to 6 Jin, it's weight
# 就把它宰了 还剩下一半
when we decided to cook it. We have a half left now
# 这一次我们这半只鸭子用这个苦瓜来烧
This time we braise this half of duck with the bitter gourd
# 我四伯上次吃那个苦瓜酿肉他觉得挺好吃的
Last time my uncle had the meat-stuffed bitter gourd, he found it quite delicious
# 然后就又用这个苦瓜来烧鸭子
So we use bitter gourd again, to braise the duck
# 现在把它剁了
Now I chop it into pieces
# 砍大坨点吗砍小坨点
Larger lumps or smaller?
# 大坨点嘛 弄来咋个吃的嘛
Bigga, how ya gonna cook it? （俺试图翻方言，要是怪怪的就改掉吧哈哈哈哈
# 给你烧苦瓜的嘛
To braise the bitter gourd for you
# 要得 一会烧得耙不哦
I'd like it. Can it be braised soft and tneder?
# 烧得耙
Definitely
# 我们这个上面没得点（鸭）绒毛的
We ain't got any feather or hair on this
# 打整得干干净净的
So neat and tidy
# 香嘎
Flavourful, isn't it?
# 是安
Yea
# 你看这冒油 我们这鸭子你看
You see this fat, our duck, see
# 它这个皮里面都在冒油
Inside its skin the fat is coming out
# 鸭肝鸭心一起放进去
Together with the liver and heart
# 好 我们现在来切这三条苦瓜
Ok, now I cut these three bitter gourd
# 这苦瓜特别的新鲜
They are very fresh
# 大家可以看一下这个（蒂）感觉是现摘下来的
You see this stem, it looks freshly-picked
# 应该摘下来只有一天 两天都不到
It should be only one day since it's picked, less than two days
# 这个不是我们的本地苦瓜嘎
This is not our local product?
# 不是的
Nah
# 好大哦
It's large
# 这热天吃了苦瓜是最安逸的
It's best to eat bitter gourd in this hot weather
# 吃了降火嘎
It brings down the "internal heat"
# 是啊 这个是清热的
Yeah, this clears the heat
# 我们用手就可以把这个抓下来
We can remove this just by our hands
# 如果你们不能吃苦的话这个可以用勺子刮干净一点
If you dislike the bitterness you may scrape it all away with a spoon
# 能吃苦的就可以不用刮得那么干净
If you like, you don't need to remove it so carefully
# 有时候苦反而是一种美味 嘎四伯爷
Sometimes the bitterness is a kind of good taste, isn't it uncle?
# 是安
Indeed!
# 我们这个苦瓜既然是烧鸭子这么大坨 那就切大一点
Since we're gonna braise the bitter gourd with these large lumps of duck, I cut them into larger pieces
# 好 我们现在再切点泡椒
Okay, now we cut some pickled chili
# 泡椒是我伯爷自己泡的
My uncle made the pickled chili by himself
# 你这个海椒有点辣哦嘎
Your chili is pretty spicy, isn't it?
# 当然了
Of course
# 这个烧苦瓜就是它本身比较苦
This braised bitter gourd, it taste bitter itself
# 就要多放点辣椒
which needs more chili pepper
# 烧东西就离不得那姜蒜
Garlic and ginger are indispensable in braised stuff
# 直接给它切成颗粒
Cut it directly into pieces
# 稍微可以大一点
A bit larger
# 大蒜一开二就可以了
Cut the garlic into just two
# 最后我们来再准备一块小小的火锅底料
Finally we get a small lump of hot pot soup base
# 上一下底味
For the basic taste
# 如果没有火锅底料的朋友可以放点豆瓣酱加猪油
If you don't have the base you may use some Doubanjiang (Sichuan bean paste) with pork lard instead
# 一样的可以起到这个效果
It will work the same
# 好 四伯爷帮我端哈
Okay, uncle help me carry some
# 走嘛
Let's go
# 直接弄来烧起
directly to cook
# 好
Good
# 首先我们这个鸭子给它放点水进去焯一下
First we parboil the duck
# 给它冷水下锅焯一下水
Drop it into the wok when the water is still cool
# 然后再放一点料酒
With a little Chinese cooking wine
# 四伯爷你看嘛这个焯水出来这个泡沫要把它打了啦
Uncle you see, the scum needs to be removed
# 这样子都焯好了
Now the parboiling is done
# 这样子慢慢的给它煎
Fry the duck leisurely
# 把那个鸭子的油给它煎出来
Until the fat comes out
# 然后差不多了就放姜蒜在里面
When it's almost done, drop the garlic and ginger in
# 还有这个泡海椒
And this pickled chili
# 好 现在我们已经差不多要爆香了
Okay, it's becoming aromatic
# 加这个火锅底料下去炒化
Add in the hotpot base, stir and fry until it melts
# 诶呀 好香哦
Aiya, it smells so good
# 加点这个老抽调哈颜色
A little dark soy sauce for the colour
# 颜色给它调深点
Colour it a bit darker
# 然后我们再放点酱油
And some light soy sauce
# 最后再放半瓶啤酒
Half a can of beer at last
# 再放一点水进去
and a few water
# 然后烧开了火稍微小点
When it's boiling, lower the heat
# 这样子烧它半小时
Braise it for half an hour
# 好了 现在我们这个已经烧了40分钟了
Okay, now our dish has been braised for 40 minutes
# 把这个苦瓜放进去了
Drop in the bitter gourd
# 苦瓜放进去的时候就开始调味
At the same time start seasoning
# 少放一点盐
A little bit salt
# 再放一点白糖
A bit sugar
# 差不多了
Almost done
# 我们这个苦瓜把它烧熟了大概需要3分钟
The bitter gourd, it takes about 3 minutes to braise
# 如果你们怕苦的话可以焯一下水
If you dislike the bitterness you can parboil it in advance
# 这个油烟子好熏人哦
The soot is quite irritating
# 熏到你了啊
It chokes you, didn't it?
# 今天这个苦瓜我就把它烧软一点
Today I'm gonna braise the bitter gourd to tender and soft
# 我伯爷他牙口不好
My uncle's teeth are not pretty good
# 要是说普通人吃的话现在都可以出锅了
If for ordinary people, the dish is ready to serve now
# 这个油烟子熏起眼泪都要熏出来
This choking soot, it almost choke my tears out
# 马上就好了哈
It's finished in a second
# 站远点的
Keep a distance
# 好 差不多了 可以了
Okay, almost there, it's done
# 好香啊
It smells so nice
# 但是苦瓜烧肉我吃过
But I've tasted meat braised with bitter gourd
# 下次给你整个苦瓜汤给你喝 要得不
What about next time I cook a bitter gourd soup for you
# 苦瓜汤整起害怕苦的要命安
I'm afraid the soup would be too bitter
# 不得 苦瓜排骨汤好喝得很
Nah, bitter gourd soup cooked with pork rib is really tasty
# 尝哈看嘛四伯爷
Have a try, uncle
# 我试哈看烧耙没有
Let me see if it's braised soft enough
# 我先吃一个苦瓜尝一下
I'll first try the bitter gourd
# 我先整这个大的鸭肉
I get this large lump of duck
# 苦瓜有点苦哦伯娘
Aunt, the gourd is a bit bitter
# 嗯 不怕
Um, nevermind
# 我没焯水的直接放下去
I didn't parboil the bitter gourd, dropped it directly in
# 嗯 整耙了的 还不苦安这个鸭肉
Um, it's tender, and this duck is not bitter at all
# 但是苦瓜苦哦
But the bitter gourd is
# 苦瓜苦哦
The bitter gourd taste bitter
# 鸭肉不苦
And the duck does not
# 吃坨苦瓜嘛
Try a lump of bitter gourd, won't you?
# 我尝一个鸭子看一下
I'll taste a piece of duck
# 有点苦
A little bitterness
# 我们这个苦瓜虽然说很苦 但是吃起来的话比较开胃
The bitter gourd is quite bitter though, but it really brings up your appetite
# 就是苦瓜还有莴笋稍微带点苦的食材
Those ingredients with a little bitter taste
# 是非常开胃下饭的
Can really whet your appetite
# 好吃
Delicious
# 可以
Good
# 可以噶
Not bad
# 苦瓜吃了好得很
Bitter gourds really benefits your health
# 伯娘都晓得
Aunt knows this
# 苦瓜这热天吃了是相当好的它是清热的嘛
It's extremely good for you to have bitter gourd in such a hot weather, since it helps clearing the "internal heat"
# 嗯
Um
# 很多人都喜欢吃这个苦瓜热天
Quite a few people love this bitter gourd, in the hot weather
# 所以我们这个鸭子嘛
So this duck
# 鸭子属于水禽然后再烧这个苦瓜
The duck is water-grown, and braised with this bitter gourd
# 是相当的开胃 还有比较降火
Very appetite-stimulating, and also
# 好 本期视频就到这里
Okay, that's all for today's video
# 大家可以在家里尝试一下用苦瓜煮汤 烧肉 烧鸭子
You can try at home, using bitter gourd to cook soup, braise meat or duck
# 还可以烧鸡
Also chicken
# 比较开胃 虽然苦
It raises your appetite, despite its bitter taste
# 但是有时候苦也是一种美味嘛
which is sometimes an enjoyable taste as well
# 是不是嘛四伯爷
Isn't it, uncle?
# 本期视频就到这里啦 拜拜
That's all, bye~
# 这个苦瓜也不算很苦
The bitterness is not very strong
# 要那种小个小个的硬的那种才苦
Those smaller ones, stiff ones, have a very strong bitter taste
# 秋苦瓜 要秋苦瓜烧起更苦 那会儿的又安逸安
Autumn bitter gourds are more bitter, which is also nice
# 我给你舀饭嘛伯娘
Let me get some rice for you, aunt
# 我给你舀饭
Have some rice